JOHN A. CALDERAIO

jcalderaiowork@gmail.com • 561.339.8182 • Gainesville, FL www.linkedin.com/in/johncalderaio

SUMMARY

I am a University-trained Computer Science Engineer with experience writing algorithms in Java, JavaScript, and C++. In addition, I have developed web applications in React and Angular, and hybrid-mobile applications using Ionic, Cordova, and React-Native. I am also familiar with Scrum and Agile methodologies from my time at Lockheed Martin and IBM. I've coded a shell in C, developed native iOS apps in Swift, and written entire business plans from scratch (including the patent).

SKILLS

Java, C++, C, JavaScript (ES5/6/7), Native iOS development (Swift), Cross-Platform iOS/Android development (React-Native, MobX, Ionic, Cordova w/ Angular), Front-End Web (React, jQuery, SASS, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS), Backend Web (PHP, JSON, REST APIs, MongoDB, Express, SQL, Oracle DBMS), GitHub

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida
Grade Point Average: 3.90/4.0
Graduated Summa Cum Laude with President's Honor Roll

Associate of Arts in General Education

Palm Beach State College, Palm Beach Gardens, Florida Grade Point Average: 4.0/4.0 Graduated Summa Cum Laude with President's Honor Roll

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

React Native Mobile Developer

February 2017 - October 2017

Parametric Solutions (PSI) - Remote

- Built an iOS/Android mobile application, which allows employees of Parametric Solutions to manage their work charges (Clients, Tasks, Dates, Hours Worked, etc.)
- Designed app using InVision, then prototyped a mockup in Sketch
- Created clever React Native components (such as tables with rows that change color depending on database update status)
- Learned about creating components, using REST calls, authentication, HTTP headers, Native iOS and Android modules, cross-platform features, styling rules with FlexBox, Node, Yarn, NPM, component "state", MobX, React Navigation, Expo, Promises, Async and Await commands, JavaScript libraries (such as Lodash, Moment, etc)
- Github more than 3,400 lines added to repository
- Tools: React Native / JavaScript / JSX / Node / Yarn / NPM / REST / Expo / MobX / NativeBase / Atom / GitHub / Sketch / InVision / Photoshop

IT Consultant March 2017 – Present

- Non-profit organization dedicated to perfecting and personalizing bionics, and implementing solutions for disabilities for free or at greatly reduced costs
- Co-founded company with one of my closest friends, Juan Casas
- Delegated tasks such as: Design of the logo, Design of the website, Creation of the website
- Assembled a team to redesign and recode website in React and develop both iOS/Android apps in React Native
- Instructed team members to complete React course on Udemy
- Currently waiting for team to finish the course
- Tools: React / React Native / JavaScript / JSX / Node / Yarn / NPM / Expo / NativeBase / Atom / GitHub

Founder and CEO

December 2016 - September 2017

Online Gainesville - Gainesville, FL

- Designed and developed website using Bootstrap and MaterializeCSS frameworks
- Acquired customers, such as SafeBriight and Parametric Solutions
- Generated over \$20k in revenue within first year of business (part-time only), without marketing or promotion

AngularJS Mobile Developer

June 2015 – August 2015

IBM - Remotely

- Helped develop a work portal (dashboard) which showed employee info and an overall view of tasks, services, processes, and claims
- Created custom directives specific to DOM manipulation, adding logic within controllers to communicate feedback to the user, and modifying angular services to retrieve variables used within the templates
- Met in daily scrum meetings where we discussed user stories and defects to ensure our objectives would be achieved by the end of each sprint
- Performed code reviews of peers submitted for my approval before being released into current software builds
- Tools: AngularJS / Cordova / JavaScript / Sublime / GitHub

Java Software Engineer

June 2014 - August 2014

Lockheed Martin - Orlando, Florida

- Designed and built an internal web app for the F-35 Lightning II Engineering Team
- Developed on JBoss using Java Servlets and JavaServer Pages within a team of software engineers
- Created functional use cases for the F-35 Lightning II Joint Strike Fighter's Autonomic Logistics Information System (ALIS) using Enterprise Architect
- Designed embedded systems utilizing Raspberry Pi, python, and circuits within a team of four to solve design challenges proposed by Lockheed Martin's Research and Development team
- Tools: Java / Java Servlets / Java Server Pages / JBoss Application Server / Windows Server 2012 / MySQL / Apache / Rasberry Pi / Python

Laboratory Chemist

August 2012 – August 2013

The Renewable Corporation, Lake Park, Florida

- Synthesized coatings that completely seal in asbestos surfaces, encapsulating hazardous materials
- Spearheaded research and reformulation team on project to increase slip resistance in all floor coatings
- Researched surface bubbling production anomaly with TRC's flagship coating product and submitted a comprehensive reformulation proposal that eliminated all inconsistencies
- Identified and corrected several situations in which pH fluctuation was affecting product shelf life, saving the company upwards of thousands of dollars per year

 Maintained stock supply levels and communicated directly with chemical distributors to optimize purchases and explore cost saving alternatives

Private Tutor March 2012 – December 2012

Palm Beach State College, Palm Beach Gardens, Florida

- Led private chemistry, calculus, and physics tutoring sessions
- Worked diligently with students to increase their comprehension of complex concepts, resulting in an increase of one letter grade by most tutees

Sales Associate March 2008 – January 2011

Nordstrom, Palm Beach Gardens, Florida

- Consistently ranked among top sales representatives in region
- Winner of over six performance contests for highest overall net sales and highest ranking in customer satisfaction
- Performed market research to obtain knowledge of competing companies and to implement sales strategies

PROJECTS

React-Native vs Swift Apps

September 2016

University of Florida, Gainesville

This was a University of Florida sanctioned research project. React-Native is Facebook's new hybrid mobile framework. It is unlike other hybrid mobile frameworks because it compiles the JavaScript to real Objective-C code for iOS and Java code for Android. Because hybrid mobile development is such a hot topic right now, and React-Native is the newest player to the game, I wanted to test how good it really was.

In order to do this, I made two identical apps - one in Swift and one in React-Native. I then used Apple Instruments to compare their performance and graph my findings. My findings showed that React-Native is in fact as performant as native iOS apps, and even slightly faster. I published a research paper summarizing my findings and was granted Summa Cum Laude highest honors for my work.

*Read my paper at: https://medium.com/the-react-native-log/comparing-the-performance-between-native-ios-swift-and-react-native-7b5490d363e2#.a7mck7ig5

No Satellite GPS September 2015

University of Florida, Gainesville

This was a University of Florida sanctioned research project. My professor wanted the Computer Science department mapped in 3D on AutoCAD and stored in a Spatial Database for offline GPS traversal.

I Utilized Ionic, AngularJS, Cordova, and SpatiaLite's JavaScript library to create a hybrid mobile Spatial Database on iOS. The Computer Science Department/AutoCAD model was then imported as a GeoJSON object into the app. The use of the app could search for a room number (for example) and the app would retrieve the JSON data from the Spatial Database.

Shell in C April 2015

- For our Operating Systems class, we had to create a Shell to run on terminal in Unix.
- Made to imitate many of Unix/Mac's terminal functionality
- Written in C using Lex & Yacc

- Used Ionic & Cordova to create a cross platform application called "Turnup" to Find and Host local Videogame tournaments
- Wrote directives in Angular to serve data
- Developed CSS & JS responsive menu
- Created member list via Parse API

University of Florida Faculty Database Sharing Web App

January 2015

A web app for UF faculty, researchers, and grad students to share databases that they use. Users can also create a portfolio so that they can keep track of databases they use, as well as add databases that they find that other users have added.

Beats Captain Database Project

September 2014

- Stored 110,001 tuples of music at random from the data on an Oracle DB backend
- Constructed a frontend using jQuery & Bootstrap
- Used PHP to query the database & for input validation

FriendMesh March 2014

- In my Engineering Entrepreneurship course, I was chosen by my professor and Dean to accompany them to Silicon Valley and present my team's mobile app to UF Alumni Donors such as Chris Malachowsky (NVIDIA Creator) and David Faircloth (a Vice President at IBM).
- Wrote and filed provisional patent pertaining to the operation of mobile application

AWARDS & AFFILIATIONS

Summa Cum Laude & Presidents Honor Roll

Member, Toastmasters University of Florida Chapter

Member, Computer Information Security Team

Martin Luther King Jr. Leadership Award, presented to the student who has made the most innovative contribution toward improving the lives of others in Palm Beach County

Vice President, Student Government Association

Outstanding Student Government Senator Award

Lead Project Engineer: NASA Reduced Gravity Education Flight Program, Florida Engineering

Society